Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/kithsiriw-8354657 (LinkedIn) guessmysoftware.blogspot.com/ (Blog) www.ca-cib.com (Company)

Top Skills

Hibernate Spring Tomcat

Languages

Sinhala (Native or Bilingual) English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Sun Certified Java Programmer Virtusa Certified Scrum Master Parallel and Concurrent Programming with Java 1

Kithsiri W.

Senior Java/J2EE Developer at Crédit Agricole CIB Singapore

Summary

11 years of diverse experience in the software industry. Dynamic and skilled IT professional with proven success in software project/product development. Experience in Enterprise Application development on the J2EE platform, design and development of Web applications. Strong troubleshooting, analytical and design skills.

Specialties: C, Oracle 10g, Java 1.6, Spring and hibernate 3, unix AIX 5, windows xp, Ext-js, GWT, DOJO, Grails, Python2.7, Django 3, EJB3, P4V, BOSaNOVA, Java Swings, LiquiBase, NodeJS, AngularJS, Quova, Squid, AJAX, Oracle Service Bus, SonicMQ, Docker, MongoDB, Redis Caching, Akamai, New Relic, AppDynamics Agile, SCRUM, KANBAN, JasperReports, Splunk, Apache Lucene, Apache POI, ElasticSearch, Alfresco, JIRA, Jenkins, Subversion, Bitbucket, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, jQuery, Apache Tomcat, Jboss, Webspehere, Rational Rose UML, Lucidchart, Struts 2, Sonar, FindBugs,Fiddler, Postman,Apache OpenNLP,RASA NLU,artificial intelligence,Microservices with Netflix stack,Harshicorp stack and AWS eco system, Hortonworks Data platform, HA deployment,JibX,Angular 9 etc.

Experience

Crédit Agricole CIB Senior JAVA/J2EE Developer October 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months) Singapore

Virtusa

6 years 9 months

Senior Consultant technology October 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 1 month) Sri Lanka development of complex, multitiered and distributed Web based software applications.

Provides technical guidance to an empowered team of 6+ software engineers on aspects

of development including adherence to the architectural & engineering best practices following agile principles.

- Coaching an agile team which consists of Software engineers, Senior Software Engineers
- The main responsibilities are to meet the given deadline with high quality products, work collaboratively with other teams to ensure the product meets required quality, make sure that the engineering best practices are met, reviewing the codes, grooming the team, work closely with the US counter parts and etc.
- Requirement gathering, analyzing and preparing the design documents when necessary.
- Analyzing the existing systems/applications to identify the improvements and propose the solutions for them
- Supporting monitoring proactively to make sure that the systems are up and running 24/7
- Demonstration of the developed feature set to the end users timely manner.

Consultant - technology March 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 7 months)

Sri Lanka

development of complex, multitiered and distributed Web based software applications.

Provides technical guidance to an empowered team of 6+ software engineers on aspects

of development including adherence to the architectural & engineering best practices following agile principles.

- Coaching an agile team which consists of Software engineers, Senior Software Engineers
- The main responsibilities are to meet the given deadline with high quality products, work collaboratively with other teams to ensure the product meets required quality, make sure that the engineering best practices are met, reviewing the codes, grooming the team, work closely with the US counter parts and etc.

- Requirement gathering, analyzing and preparing the design documents when necessary.
- Analyzing the existing systems/applications to identify the improvements and propose the solutions for them
- Supporting monitoring proactively to make sure that the systems are up and running 24/7
- Demonstration of the developed feature set to the end users timely manner.

Associate Consultant - Technology May 2015 - February 2016 (10 months) Sri Lanka

Attend to client meetings and gathering the requirements with the support of business analyst and rest of the team.

participating on requirement elicitation meetings.

Starting designing phase with the team members and doing the review with architect, doing necessary changes if needed after the discussions.

Assign multiple tasks among the team in association with project manager.

Assisting juniors in difficult problem solving situations.

Starting the development phase on fine grained designing in TDD approach with the help of QA leadership.

Configuring the lower test environments as needed

Involve in unit testing and integration testing in lower environments.

participate in code reviews and suggest refactoring accordingly.

Handover the feature demo each member of the team.

Associate Consultant - Technology May 2014 - May 2015 (1 year 1 month) Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Worked at client location (Standard Chartered Bank Sdn Bhd)

Duties and responsibilities were related to kind of support activities plus software system designing and developments.

Once an issue reported try to clarify with the client if needed.

Involve in resolution of the issue and if there any modification to be done review it and engage in designing of new change then close the task in Remedy ticketing system.

Associate Consultant - Technology February 2012 - May 2014 (2 years 4 months) Sri Lanka

Requirement elicitation with business analyst Software designing with UML and review them the team lead and architect Start the test cases then development
Involve in unit testing activities
Involve in integration testing
Involve in system testing
Finally doing demonstration to the developed feature to the client

OpenArc Systems Management (pvt) Ltd Software Engineer December 2010 - February 2012 (1 year 3 months) Sri Lanka

Following waterfall approach to build the projects

Collecting and discussing product requirements with business analyst to clarify them.

Designing of the software system and also review closely them with technical leads and architects

Starting the POCs and developments with the team

While developing take care of the functionality testing as well

Bellvantage

Associate software engineer March 2008 - December 2010 (2 years 10 months)

Worked on BVCP(Bellvantage collaboration platform), rating and billing module in Bellvantage and Lanka bell. GWT, Spring, hibernate, struts, grails and relevant J2EE technologies are applied with those systems front end development and also backend. While the development environments are basically on UNIX AIX and windows xp. Most of the time backend operations is being done with PL/SQL, functions and procedures on Oracle RDBMS.

IJTS

Trainee J2EE developer August 2007 - February 2008 (7 months)

The developments were started as trainee java developer with struts 1.3.8, hibernate and RDBMS was postgresSQL. Mainly worked on Hotel reservation system with web services request response handling part, Student registration system, Online photo gallery and Eloan system.

Education

BCS, The Chartered Institute for IT

BSc equivalent, Computer Software · (2008 - 2010)

Page 4 of 5

Dudley Senanayeke Central College · (1997 - 2005)

Dudley Senanayeke Central College
Advanced Level in physics, chemistry, biology · (1997 - 2004)